Guide to the Klaus Ebeling Ragamala painting research collection, 1952-1973.
Ragamala, Klaus Ebeling painting research collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Klaus Ebeling Ragamala painting research collection, 1952-1973.
8400
Ebeling, Klaus.
3 cubic feet.
Photographs, publications, research materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Research collection of photographic slides, publications, and notes on Ragamala painting.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Research collection of photographic slides, publications, and notes on Ragamala painting. Materials were gathered while Ebeling was conducting research for his book Ragamala Painting, published in 1973.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ebeling, Klaus.
Subjects:
Rāgamālā painting.; Miniature painting, Indic.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Research, drafts, and publications
Series II. Visual materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Research, drafts, and publications
  - Ragamala Painting by Klaus Ebeling, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Ragamala Painting bound galley proof, ca. 1973 (Box 1)
  - Bound research articles (Box 1)
  - Ragamala Painting galley proof, ca. 1973 (Box 2)
  - Ragamala research notes, three bound volumes (Box 2)
  - Miniature Painting by Karl Khandavala, Moti Chandra, and Pramod Chandra. Bound photocopy, 1960 (Box 2)
  - The Laud Ragamala Paintings by Herbert J. Stooke. Bound photocopy, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Problems of Rajasthani Painting by Karl Khandalavala. Bound photocopy (Box 2)
  - The Early Rajput Murals of Bairat (Ca. A.D. 1587) by H. Goetz. Bound photocopy (Box 2)
  - Malwa Painting by Anand Krishna. Bound photocopy (Box 2)
  - Confusing Iconographies in Rajput Ragamalas reprint, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Bound photocopies of articles cited in Ragamala Painting (Box 2)
  - Binder 4: Miscellaneous items related to Ragamala Painting (Box 2)
- Series II. Visual materials
  - Binder of Research photographs for Ragamala Painting, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Slide box 1: Ragamalas from Amber, Mewar, Marwar and Unknown Schools, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Slide box 2: Ragamalas from the Deccan, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Slide box 3: Illustrations from OC Gangoly's Ragas and Raginis Vol. II, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Slide box 4: Ragamalas from Jaipur, 18th century, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Slide box 5: Pahari and provincial Mughal ragamalas, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Slides of Ragamalas from Malwa, Bundi/Kotah, Sirohi, Mewar, and Amber Schools, 1969-1970 (Box 4)